Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Planet Balun
Space-time fluctuation has increased from zel 050 to zel 070.
No change to estimated arrival time.
Balun Guard Force HQ
7th Squadron will proceed to dock 5.
6th and 13th Destroyer Groups will enter at dock 9.
Port crew, begin anchoring ships.
Mechanics, stand by for further orders.
Here are Lord Desler's orders.
Effective tam 12:08, Domel, Commander of the Small Magellanic Cloud Defense Forces,
is appointed Milky Way Theatre Operations Commander.
His predecessor, Goer, will serve as his second-in-command.
That is all.
Sir, a message from Flaken.
"The Wolf has danced with the Sheep."
Has something happened?
The hound seems to have found its prey.
Two enemy spatial torpedoes have crashed into the planetesimal.
Distance 3,000 km.
Another attempt to find us.
As long as we hide within this protostar's interstellar medium,
finding the Yamato will be very difficult.
Your decision was excellent.
But where did they come from?
Anything on radar?
No, I couldn't locate them last time, either.
So they're stealthed?
We've been here four hours. We can't stay forever...
Another incoming.
Hit! At ten o'clock, distance 200.
Close hyperspace vents. Adjust course from 22 to 30.
Dimensional pressure normal.
Phase displacement parameters normal.
Unable to detect Dimensional Wave Motion pattern.
They aren't taking the bait.
With this much interstellar medium, we can't track their spatial wake.
Intelligent little rats.
The smarter the prey, the better.
Heini, we shall enjoy ourselves during this war.
Small dimensional quakes?
Captain, this is just a guess,
but the enemy may be using a ship able to create a corridor into a dimensional rift.
Captain?
Captain!
Doctor, what is this?
We need to operate. Get started.
Yes, sir.
As XO, I will take command until
Captain Okita is fit to return to duty.
We will assume that the enemy ship is capable of interdimensional flight.
Niimi and Mori, try to track the enemy.
Yes, sir.
A ship that can travel to other dimensions...
Dimensional Submarine UX01 is
under His Lordship's direct control.
I'm amazed that his office permitted you to bring it here.
They didn't.
What did you say?
Don't worry, sir.
The hound's owner is Admiral Ditz.
In other words, if old man Ditz agrees, there's no problem.
The problem will be Captain Flaken...
You've got that right.
He's not an easy man to command.
My motto is adaptability above all else.
Keep that in mind, Goer.
Z-Zar Balk...
Blood pressure is 120 over 75. Pulse is 60.
Captain, I'll save you.
Begin the operation!
Activating medical drone.
Medical nanomachines on standby.
Well?
Captain!
Our prey is smart. And frightened.
They're waiting for us to make the first move.
How long are we staying here? Damn it all!
The officers know what they're doing.
But the Captain collapsed, right? He won't die, will he?
Yabu!
Boss! When did you get here?
Don't worry, Yabu. He won't die.
That will not happen. Understood?
Yes, sir!
Sweat.
Any movement?
Even if they can submerge dimensionally, their ability to stay must have a limit.
They'll show themselves eventually.
So we keep waiting, huh?
You're too tense.
It's difficult to wait, isn't it?
Yes.
We've been waiting a long time with no luck. Maybe they're already dead.
You're right.
I'm getting tired of hide and seek.
Let's give something a try...
Another 400cc's of blood.
The operation is over.
XO, if you know anything, please tell me.
Kodai...
What's wrong with the Captain?
Ship on radar. Four o'clock, distance 28,000.
Wavelength is specific to Garmillas ships. That must be it.
Enemy is leaving the system.
Which means...
They gave up and left.
No, it's too soon to assume they're gone.
Do you have any evidence?
I do not. If I had to say, call it intuition.
It runs in the family, huh?
I said I agree.
XO, why don't we use the warp engine's subsystems as a hyperspace transducer?
If we use the dimensional fault data to set the parameters,
we should be able to fire a sonar ping
across the dimensional boundary layer.
Dimensional active sonar, huh? That would
show if they're hiding in another dimension.
But it would also reveal our position.
You can't let fear paralyze you.
I suggest using the Seagull to patrol for hostiles.
The new hyperspace sonar buoy?
Yes, it works using the same principle.
Then we should be able to find any hidden enemies.
Theoretically.
But sending the Seagull out in all this space dust is suicide.
But if the enemy is still there, we could search without revealing our position.
And who will you order to undertake this dangerous mission?
I'll do it.
No.
XO?
This is only for confirmation.
Niimi's plan is more realistic.
But...
No. Niimi, prepare the pinger.
Yes, sir.
CIC, this is Sado.
The Captain's operation is over.
It was a success.
XO Sanada, why don't you send
someone to check on the Captain?
Leave the bridge to us.
You need the courage to disobey an order you believe is wrong, to remain true to yourself.
That is what I think.
You came to see him?
Take good care of the Captain.
Don't do anything stupid.
Inputting Wave Motion parameters.
Confirmed.
Kitano entering.
Are you ready, AU09?
You're late!
I'm sorry.
Charge complete.
Prepare for sonar ping.
Hyperspace transducer standing by.
The hyperspace sonar buoy?
That's right. As soon as it's loaded, I'll go out.
Well, it's already loaded.
They say to stay one step ahead.
Enomoto!
You remember that from training, don't you?
Now, get going... We're launching the Seagull.
But the order...
...hasn't been issued.
I've already taken care of it.
And you two will accompany me in the Seagull, to assist the Tactical Officer.
Firing dimensional sonar pinger.
Prepare to track the enemy.
Fire the sonar pinger.
Firing!
There it is! They fell for the decoy...
They didn't know we were here, the fools.
You traced that pinger, right?
Yes, sir.
Should we do it? We're doing it, right?
Rise to dimensional periscope depth.
Blow dimensional tanks!
Let the hunt begin.
Dimensional sonar pinger detecting a ship.
Something rising to the dimensional boundary layer.
They're tracing our pinger.
Start the engine! We're getting out of here.
Raise anchor!
I found you...
Prepare the torpedoes!
Open torpedo tubes 1 and 2!
XO, hangar on port side is opening!
What?
Seagull, no launch order has been issued.
Who's on board?
S-Seriously?
Seagull launching.
Um, are we disobeying orders?
Quit whining, and get to work.
What?
Yes, sir!
Torpedo parameters are set.
Fire torpedo tubes 1 and 2.
Firing tubes 1 and 2!
Seagull, come in. Who's on board? Seagull!
Something is approaching the Yamato at high speed.
These are torpedoes! Two of them!
No...
Shima!
Evading.
Second torpedo approaching!
You've gotten better.
I had a good teacher.
Thanks.
Hey, where's the Yamato?
External armor has been penetrated. Air leakage. Rapid pressure loss.
Engine output dropping.
Seal deck 10!
That sonar ping came back to bite us, huh?
Damage control.
This is the Seagull. Seagull to Yamato.
Kodai?
Dropping hyperspace sonar buoy.
So it was you!
What do you think you're doing?!
Scary...
Dropping now... Iwata! Toyama!
Aye aye, sir...
Dropping buoys!
Our prey is tough.
Tubes 3 and 4... Fire!
Yamato, do you read? This is the Seagull.
I'll send estimated appearance points for the torpedoes.
Use the data to shoot them down.
Listen...
Weapons Officer, prepare to intercept torpedoes.
Understood. Prepare to intercept torpedoes!
Prepare to intercept torpedoes!
Looks like we found them.
Two torpedoes!
Transmit data to the Yamato.
Roger!
Coordinates entered.
Intercept those torpedoes.
Open fire!
They anticipated our firing angle.
You're kidding.
Again?
They don't quit, do they?
They can see us, but we're at the bottom of another dimension. They can't touch us.
So that's it?
What?
What's this?
Something's emerging from the dimensional boundary layer!
Where?
Nearby!
Confirming... Take us there.
Can you see it?
There it is!
This is the Seagull.
We're seeing an apparent enemy probe at four o'clock, behind the Yamato.
Sending coordinates.
Knock it out, and we'll blind them.
He's every bit as reckless, too.
Prepare to fire!
Inputting coordinates!
Target is in our sights. Open fire!
They got us.
Commencing approach. Pre-landing check.
Preparing to dock.
As soon as the Seagull docks, we leave at top speed.
Once we're out of the system, we'll use warp to lose them.
Nothing on radar.
The bastards jumped. What do we do?
For now, we'll allow them to go.
You're sure?
A good hound never chases too far.
Captain...
Kodai?
And Tokugawa, too.
Is the Yamato all right?
Somehow, we made it through.
Thanks to the young ones.
Though it seems you went a bit too far.
But Sanada has arranged it so that you won't be disciplined.
You can't tell from his face, but he isn't a bad guy.
I see.
You didn't want to let him die, did you?
That's why you didn't agree to his plan.
But he believed he was doing the right thing, and he acted anyway.
What do you think he would've done?
Probably the same thing as Kodai...
You're right.
Episode 13
The Wolf from Another Dimension
Believe that
Only the future
Has the answer
No one knows
Memory only strikes at
The heart to find
The truth
Do not forget it…
Many stars lie beyond
The spiral of memory
Sparkling in what looks like
The light of memory
A siren's song lures ships to their doom.
Snow falls in the emptiness of the void, where a shadow of evil prowls.
The Yamato is shipwrecked.
And inside, no one is to be found.
What will Kodai and the others see there?
Next time: The Whisper of the Witch.
There are 310 days left before humanity is extinct.